out Rima standing by now to take us
through what Q4 looks like Rima well
this is turning out to be a
disappointing quarter for enforces it's
a missing Revenue it's a missing margins
and the fi-24 guidance is coming in
lower than what the street was
anticipating the markets were fearing a
weak set of numbers which is why the
stock ended with a cut of 2.7 but this
is a much weaker showing compared to TCS
as well let me run you through the
numbers constant currency Revenue growth
has fallen by 3.2 percent yes it's
Fallen by 3.2 percent the the most
bearish bearish estimate in the street
was a minus 0.1 percent the company has
delivered a decline of 3.2 percent okay
the last time we had such a big decline
in the revenues was in the covet
quarters so minus 3.2 percent is the
constant currency Revenue growth margins
also have fallen by 50 basis points at
21 it falls short of expectations of
21.5 percent so minus ah you know 3.2
percent on the top line and margins
declining by 50 basis points to 21 both
these parameters are much weaker than
what we were anticipating the bigger
problem is going to be the guidance for
next year the company is guiding for a
revenue growth of four to seven percent
okay this is you know compared to our
expectations of about six to eight
percent or even five to seven percent uh
there are two points to this one the
guidance is much lower than what the
street was anticipating and two given
the uncertainty they have widened the
revenue band typically when they give
you a revenue Guidance the band is 200
basis points because you want to account
for some uncertainty when you give a 300
basis points a revenue ban that's four
to seven percent it's accounting for a
lot of uncertainty so that's uh the Miss
in terms of the revenue performance
margins too have come in lower than what
the street was anticipating their ebit
margin guide then stands at 20 to 22
percent versus the CNBC TV 18 poll of 21
to 23 percent
um you know and uh just to you know put
it in context in fy23 the margins were
at 21 which basically means they're not
expecting margins to improve from here
or not and here the key reason would be
no operating leverage if your revenues
are not there it's very hard to grow
margins so margins too have come in
lower than what the street was
anticipating salil parekh the CEO and MD
says as the environment has changed we
see a strong interest from our clients
for efficiency cost and consolidating or
consolidation opportunities resulting in
a strong large deal pipeline we have
expanded our internal program on
efficiency and cost to build a path to
higher margins in the medium term we
continue to invest in our people and in
supporting uh clients so the fy24 for
guidance is a miss four to seven percent
Revenue growth margins at 20 to 22 so
there is no expansion in margins that
they are anticipating and just to I
think put it in context uh this four to
seven percent growth will compare with a
15.4 percent growth that they've seen in
fy23 so there is a sharp drop-off that
we've seen and also the fy23 revenue
growth of 15.4 percent is missing the
company's guidance uh the deal wins are
pretty healthy 2.1 billion dollars but
this is lower than the deal wins that we
had in the prior quarter so this is an
across-the-board Miss and it's an across
the board very big miss little Shah head
of research add Reliance Securities is
now with us on the show uh middle I'm
trying to find some Silver Linings that
perhaps we can latch on to the order
book number where 2.1 billion dollars is
the deal wins announced by enforces in
Q4 which is lower on a quarter on
quarter basis but largely in line with
their long-term average but on all other
parameters on Q4 fy24 guidance it's a
big Miss
yes there is a big Miss across the
account even dilwin is lower q and Q as
well as it is much lower than Q2 numbers
also and revenue means inspect instead
of growth it is coming decline that is
really a surprising because in the
company's geography wise performance
Europe has done far better than our
expectations so problem is coming from
North America and even if we look at
vertical wise details then there is a
sizable decline in contribution from
bfsi segment so we can make out that
issue is from North America as well as
bfsi segment within entire space for the
company
okay I'm still trying to call out the
bfsi in the North America numbers but
just to put the minus 3.2 constant
currency Revenue growth uh to put those
numbers into context even in the coveted
headquarters the revenue growth decline
was not as much in Q4 f520 which is the
March quarter which had about a one
month or a 15-day impact of covet the
revenues had fallen by minus 0.8 percent
in the following quarter which was the
most severe the April to June period of
uh you know 2020
um in the immediate aftermath the
revenues for infy had declined by minus
two percent okay so this minus 3.2
percent is much worse than what we had
seen in covet and as I said no one on
the street anticipated such a large
decline in their revenues this is coming
as an absolute Shocker on the way down
for those of you who've just tuned in
even though we were bracing ourselves
for a weak set of numbers after tcs's
Poor showing uh enforces numbers are
really surprising on the downside
constant currency Revenue growth has
fallen 3.2 percent on a quarter on
quarter basis the street was
anticipating a modest growth margins
have fallen by 50 basis points to 21
again missing the mark their fy24
guidance is for a four to seven percent
growth so on one hand they have also
widened their revenue uh guidance back
four to seven percent Compares with a
15.4 percent growth that they've
delivered in fy23 and margins too the
street was hoping for some sort of a
margin expansion because the supply side
of the equation had started improving
with lower attrition and fewer hires but
that doesn't appear to be the case the
company's margin guidance ban stands at
20 to 22 percent which Compares with 21
to 22 that they had guided for in F5 23.
so this is turning out to be a big
disappoint women trying to get some more
internal uh details middle do you have
the bfsi numbers if you could share it
with us
so bfsi vertical contribution is 29.3
percent compared to previous quarter it
was 31.5 uh 30.5 percent okay and prior
to that 31.5
okay and uh do you have some more
numbers on attrition and are there any
other verticals which have seen a big
fall or a big miss or is this only bfsi
so now it seems that it is bfsi related
major issue and in terms of this
employee Edition also this is a very
important point to note that there is a
negative employee Edition or there is a
employee reduction to the tune of 3000
head counts so despite that there is a
pressure on the employee cost side
and very interesting thing uh from these
guidance as well as yesterday's PCS
commentary we should note that both the
management earlier few other management
highlighted January was descent or
reasonably strong but February and March
has witnessed deterioration
so that means that still within the
quarter performance of one month was
much stronger and if we assume that
similar Trend to continue for next few
months then certainly next quarter would
be if sizable deterioration on Q and Q
basis from here on across the I.T
coverage okay and that is a real
challenge for next two quarters for the
industry okay one more uh metric which
does indicate perhaps that things are
slowing down meaningfully is the hiring
number or the increase in the head count
and the total employee base has fallen
by almost three and a half thousand
employees on a quarter on quarter basis
one reason for that is because the
companies have enough people on their
bench they're over hired maybe in the
first half of there when things were
looking up and now perhaps they don't
need more people but the second way to
look at it is also that it's signaling a
significant demand moderation which is
why the people who have stepped out
they're not looking to replace it so the
total employee head count has fallen by
three and a half thousand and this is
one of the lead indicators of demand
slowdown secondly on nutrition yes it's
moderated quite significantly the
voluntary attrition is at 20.9 percent
which Compares with 24.3 percent the
prior quarter so we have seen a fall of
about 340 basis points in the attrition
numbers on a quarter and quarter basis
the problem is really that the top line
has you know completely evaporated for
the company the growth in the top line
and that's the reason why despite
attrition coming down the head count
coming down margins for the company have
fallen the problem is predominantly the
financial sector uh you know bfsi has
seen a modest growth of 0.4 percent on a
year-on year basis uh to put it in
context the company's growth rate was
8.8 percent you know up until now we
were talking about the quarter on
quarter numbers but you know infy gives
the vertical breakup or the business
segment vertical breakup in on a year
near basis so 8.8 percent is the company
average now you need to reference all
the vertical growth to that 8.8 percent
so bfsi is 0.4 percent practically means
no growth compared to the prior year
this is about 30 percent of 29 percent
of the overall Revenue another vertical
which is seen a meaningful slowdown is
communication eleven twelve percent of
their revenues that has seen a growth of
just 0.3 percent so communication has
slowed down and high tech continues to
remain very muted high tech has just
seen uh lower than company average
growth of 3.4 percent uh North America
is a slow vertical and rest of the world
world as well has slowed down for them
and India business too has seen a fall
of 7.1 percent on a year on year basis
so North America is weak India is also
fairly weak for enforces this time uh
week week showing uh Shireen trying to
get more details and I think the
management commentary will provide more
clarity for the you know negative growth
that we've seen in Q4 and What's led to
such a weak guidance
absolutely
absolutely and uh we are a couple of
minutes away uh Rima from the management
speaking to us so we will of course wait
to see what they have to say but you
know I was just listening into what
mittal was saying uh and that really uh
you know takes me back to the
conversations that we were having in
January where most of the tech CEOs that
we spoke to said look so far demand
seems to be holding up and it clearly
seems that Feb and March have turned out
to be a very different story and as you
were pointing out it is bfsi which is
hurting both for tcss as well now for
Infosys and this is going to be a pocket
of pain to watch out for Rima uh no
absolutely you know what TCS said was
very telling he said that at the
beginning of the quarter in January we
were penciling in a pickup in North
America then February and March happened
the Regional Crisis the regional Banks
crisis in U.S banks were in a rush to
conserve Capital discretionary projects
were put on hold all non-essential
projects were paused or differed for
some time which is why the revenue is
completely dried out so if you are
anticipating a revenue growth of one and
a half to two percent as you know Rajesh
was telling us and these were our costs
they were expecting to make a margin but
now that Revenue fell down because
discretionary projects were you know put
on hold they didn't get that anticipated
Revenue but the costs remained where
they were and margins turned out to be
absolutely flat and in the case of
enforces margins have fallen so bfsi
projects appear to have been hit
discretionary projects have been put on
hold and there is a spillover into other
sectors as well as TCS said TC has also
flagged off manufacturing Auto in the
call yesterday they even spoke about
retail and high tech and turning out to
be a bit cautious so it's largely bfsi
but there is always a ripple effect when
the consumer sentiment turns South
yeah absolutely and we will of course
get more color from the management as we
speak with them in a few